vivino.com 2019-04-26

# Vivino Privacy Policy

This policy is effective from May 25 2018. 

This Privacy Policy describes how and when Vivino collects, uses and shares your personal information ("information") when you use our Services. Vivino receives your information through our website and our app (the "Services" or "Vivino"). For example, you send us information when you use Vivino from our website, or take a photo with our app. When using any of our Services you consent to the collection, transfer, manipulation, storage, disclosure and other uses of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

This privacy policy sets out how Vivino uses and protects any information that you give Vivino when you use our website, app or other products. 

Vivino is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. 

**For the purpose of the European Union General Data Protection Regulation, the data controller is VIVINO ApS, Njalsgade 21G, 1., 2300 Copenhagen S, Denmark, company registration number DK32081193.**

As a company, Vivino operates in many countries. Irrespective of which country you reside in or supply information from, you authorize Vivino to use your information in the United States and any other country where Vivino operates. 

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, please contact our data protection officer at [privacy@vivino.com](mailto:privacy@vivino.com). 

  1. You have the right to request access to and receive information about the information we maintain about you, update and correct inaccuracies in your information, and have the information blocked or deleted, as appropriate. You also have the right to object to our processing of your information and withdraw your consent to our processing of your information at any time. 

The right to access information may be limited in some circumstances by local law requirements. 

Please note that you may not be able to benefit from all features if you request the deletion of your information, object or withdraw your consent to the processing of your information.You have the right to data portability and we will provide you with the information we store about you on request. 

You can control your personal information from the Settings page on our website, [www.vivino.com](https://www.vivino.com/). If you have any questions or requests regarding your personal information that you cannot find an answer to on our Settings page, please contact our customer support at [support@vivino.com](mailto:support@vivino.com). 

You can complain about the processing of your information to the Danish Data Protection Agency, Borgergade 28, 5., 1300 Copenhagen K, Denmark. E-mail: dt@datatilsynet.dk. 

  2. Vivino complies with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) which protects your personal information. In this Privacy Policy we will describe what information you provide or we gather about you, why we do so, and how we use it. 

If you are a registered user of our Services, we provide you with tools and account settings to access or modify the personal information you provided to us and associated with your account. 

You can at any time revoke your consent to our Privacy Policy by deleting your Vivino account. **This can be done from the Settings section on our website, Vivino.com**. 

When you delete your account, all personally identifiable information is deleted from our systems. Content that can be fully anonymized, like ratings of wines, will not be deleted, but instead disconnected from your deleted account and will no longer be traceable back to you. 

Please remember that if you just delete the Vivino app from your phone, your Vivino account and information remains on our servers. In other words, if you want to delete your Vivino data, it is not enough to delete the app – you need to delete your account via the Settings page on our website. 

You can at any time change your consent to different types of communication from Vivino. **This can be done from the Settings section on our website, Vivino.com.**

  3. We collect and use your information below to provide our Services and to measure and improve them over time. If you use Vivino Checkout to purchase products, we also use your information to fulfill your order. 

We process your information based on the legal basis of your consent, to fulfill our contractual obligations or based on our legitimate interests in processing the information. 

  4. When using Vivino with default settings, you have a **publicly** available Vivino-account, where other users can follow your activity, namely your ratings and reviews of wines. This is because Vivino at heart is a community of wine-lovers, and our mission is to make everybody smarter about wine by facilitating the sharing of wine experiences and knowledge. 

If you want your wine-experiences to be private, you can change your Privacy Setting from "Anyone" to "Nobody" in the app or the website. You can also chose the setting "Invite only", which means that only Vivino accounts that you have specifically allowed can see your activity – like your friends or family. 

  5. When you sign up to Vivino, you may provide an email address. If you install the Vivino app you may also give your consent to notifications from Vivino on your smartphone. You can at any time unsubscribe from any and all communication from Vivino through our Settings page, both emails and notifications. All emails we send will include a link to directly unsubscribe. 

Vivino does NOT sell your communication data to 3rd parties, and by signing up to Vivino you will only receive communication from Vivino, no one else. 

  6. When using Vivino, you can choose to connect to certain social media, like Twitter, Facebook and Google Plus. This only happens if you explicitly chose to do so. Vivino can then fetch your list of friends from these sites, so that you can easily find your friends on Vivino. Vivino does not get access to contacting your friends through the social media, nor would we do so if it became possible. 

When connecting to social media through Vivino, you can also choose to share specific actions from Vivino to the social media. This only happens if you explicitly choose to do so. Please note that when you share content from Vivino to other platforms, the shared content is from then on governed by the privacy policies of those networks. 

Vivino does NOT sell your social media friend list to any 3rd party. 

  7. When signing up for Vivino, you can choose to create a user account. This is useful if you want to use Vivino across multiple devices, or ensure access to your data when switching to a new phone. 

When you create or reconfigure a Vivino account, you provide some personal information, such as your name, username, password, and email address. Some of this information, for example, your name and username, is listed publicly on our Services, including on your profile page and in search results. 

You may use your account settings to unsubscribe from notifications from Vivino. You may also unsubscribe by following the instructions contained within the notification or the instructions on our website. We may use your contact information to help others find your Vivino account, including through third-party services and client applications. 

Your account settings control whether others can find you by your email address. If you email us, we may keep your message, email address and contact information to respond to your request. If you connect your Vivino account to your account on another service in order to cross-post between Vivino and that service, the other service may send us your registration or profile information on that service and other information that you authorize. This information enables cross-posting. 

Our Services are designed to help you share information with the world. Our default is almost always to make the information you provide public for as long as you do not delete it from Vivino, but we generally give you settings to make the information more private if you want. Your public information is broadly and instantly disseminated. For instance, your public user profile information may be searchable by search engines. When you share information or content like photos or ratings via the Services, you should think carefully about what you are making public. 

While using Vivino, you can choose to provide further information that will be linked to your account: 

    * Pictures of wines
    * Ratings of wines
    * Reviews of wines
    * Likes and Comments on other users activity

All the above is voluntary and only created and collected at your initiative. 

Location Information: You may choose to add your location in your Scans. We may use and store information about your location to provide features of our Services, such as creating lists of availability of certain wines. 

  8. As you use our website and app, we use digital tracking tools, like website cookies, to track your actions. We do this to find bugs and errors in our systems, to understand what features are popular and not popular, and to personalize your product experience. For example, if you look at a lot of white wines, we will use this data to surface wine recommendations that match your preference, or recommend you to follow like-minded users on Vivino. 

Cookies: Like many websites, we use "cookie" technology to collect additional website usage data and to improve our Services, but we do not require cookies for many parts of our Services such as searching and looking at public user profiles. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your computer's hard disk. Vivino may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to better understand how you interact with our Services, to monitor aggregate usage by our users and web traffic routing on our Services, and to customize and improve our Services. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. However, some Services may not function properly if you disable cookies. 

Log Data: Our servers automatically record information ("Log Data") created by your use of the Services. Log Data may include information such as your IP address, browser type, operating system, the referring web page, pages visited, location, your mobile carrier, device and application IDs, search terms, and cookie information. We receive Log Data when you interact with our Services, for example, when you visit our websites, sign into our Services or interact with our email notifications. Vivino uses Log Data to provide our Services and to measure, customize, and improve them. If not already done earlier, we will either delete Log Data or remove any common account identifiers, such as your username, full IP address, or email address, after 18 months. 

  9. We engage service providers to perform functions and provide services to us in the United States and abroad. We may share your private personal information with such service providers subject to confidentiality obligations consistent with this Privacy Policy, and on the condition that the third parties use your private personal data only on our behalf and pursuant to our instructions. 

Law and Harm: Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Policy, we may preserve or disclose your information if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect Vivino's rights or property. However, nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to limit any legal defenses or objections that you may have to a third party's, including a government's, request to disclose your information. 

Business Transfers: In the event that Vivino is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. The promises in this Privacy Policy will apply to your information as transferred to the new entity. 

  10. Vivino is a marketplace, and as such we need to share the information needed to complete your order with the merchant partner that holds the wine. When you buy wine on Vivino, the name of the merchant partner is displayed to you. 

When you buy wine on Vivino, you need to provide information needed to ensure that you get your wine and that you have a great customer experience. This information includes 

    * The wine you ordered
    * Your name
    * Your postal address
    * Phone number
    * Email address
    * Payment information
    * Delivery preferences

If you submit an order request through Vivino Checkout, we will share the order request and the order information with the licensed seller of alcohol ("Seller") that Vivino has partnered with to fulfill your order request. Prior to the final submission of your order request, Vivino Checkout identifies the specific Seller to which your order request and order information will be submitted. Consult the Seller's privacy policy for further information regarding the Seller's collection, use, and sharing of the order information. 

We store your information as long as you have a profile on our website or in our app. If you have used Vivino Checkout we store your information for record keeping for a period of 3 years. 

The information we share with the merchant partner is: 

    * The wine you ordered
    * Your name
    * Your postal address
    * Delivery preferences

We do NOT share your phone number, email address or payment information, as this is not needed for the partner to deliver the wine. According to our merchant contracts, it is not allowed for our merchant partners to contact you via your postal address outside of the specific wine transaction. 

  11. Our Services are not directed to persons under 13. If you become aware that your child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us at [privacy@vivino.com](mailto:privacy@vivino.com). We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the child's account. You can find additional resources for parents and teens here. 

  12. Vivino complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield framework of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Privacy Shield framework, and to view our certification, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce website <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list> . 

  13. We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most current version of the policy will govern our use of your information and will always be at <https://www.vivino.com/privacy>. If we make a change to this policy that, in our sole discretion, is material, we will notify you via an @Vivino update or email to the email address associated with your account. By continuing to access or use the Services after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy. 

Effective: May 25, 2018
